# **Chelsea Leonhardt**

chelsleonhardt@gmail.com | https://locustspawning.github.io/Portfolio | linkedin.com/in/c-leonhardt | 856-535-6421 | https://www.behance.net/chelsealeonhardt

# **Experience**

#### Rosie's Farm Market Website Redesign

Freelance | October 2023 - January 2024

- Created wireframes along with high fidelity prototypes using Figma.
- Performed competitor analysis, heuristic evaluation, and stakeholder interviews.
- Developed website from ideation to deployment using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

#### In Bloom Case Study

Independent Research | September 2022

- Performed competitor analysis, Usability testing, persona creation, and UX strategy.
- Developed wireframes, journey maps, qualitative and quantitative research along with high fidelity prototypes using Figma.

### **Depth Case Study**

Independent Research | September 2022 - October 2022

- Performed competitor analysis, Usability testing, persona creation, and UX strategy.
- Developed wireframes, journey maps, qualitative and quantitative research along with high fidelity prototypes using Figma.

#### STEM Educator

Clearview Middle School | September 2021 - Current Position

- Designed the STEM curriculum focusing on science and engineering practices.
- Implemented engaging lessons centered around collaboration and communication.
- Presented information in a relatable and comprehensible format for students of all levels.

# **Education**

#### **Rowan University**

M.A. STEM Education | 2018 - 2019

- Studied under full academic scholarship.
- Focus on Biological and Life Sciences.

#### **Rowan University**

B.A. Biology | 2017 - 2018

Minor in Psychology.

#### **Design Course with Gary Simon**

Design Certification | 2023

- Foundation of Design Principles
- Focus on Figma

# Google UX Design Certificate

UX Certification | 2022

Foundation of UX Principles

# **Skills**

#### Design

 $\label{eq:User_Experience} \mbox{ $\cup$ User Interface $\cdot$ Wireframing $\cdot$ } \\ \mbox{Low-High Fidelity Mockups } \mbox{ $\cdot$ Solution Oriented}$ 

#### Research

User Interviews · User Testing · Information Architecture · Journey Mapping · Competitor Analysis · Design Strategy

#### Software

Figma · Adobe XD · Adobe Photoshop · HTML · CSS · Javascript · Python · Linux · Wacom Tablet · Krita · Gimp (working knowledge)

# Visual Design

Branding · Typography · Iconography · Web Design · Colorist · Sketch Artist

#### Other Skills

Rapid iteration · Cross-functional Collaboration and

Communication · Active Listener · Empathy · Presentation

Skills · Love for Learning

# **About**

My journey in UX design has been more than just pixels and wireframes; it's been a constant exploration of creating meaningful connections between technology and users. Each project is an opportunity to blend creativity with functionality, and seeing users seamlessly interact with the end product is my goal. Design, for me, is not just a skill set; it's a journey of making the digital world more intuitive, accessible, and aesthetically pleasing. The joy and fulfillment I derive from my work come from the profound impact of solving real-world problems through thoughtful design solutions.

